Jorge Alejandro Weiss

JorgeWeiss.com | linkedin.com/in/jorgeweiss1 | github.com/JAWeiss89

Summary:

I'm a Software Engineer specializing in Python and JavaScript for back-end development. For the past few months I've been a software engineer student at the school Springboard where I meet with senior-level engineers on a weekly basis for mentorship and to undergo code review for my work. I'm currently learning Java independently for future projects.

Skills:

Back-End Frameworks: Flask (Python), Express(JavaScript/NodeJS)

Database: PostgreSQL(RDBMS), SQL-Alchemy(ORM)

Front-End: HTML5/CSS3/ES6+, Bootstrap, jQuery, AJAX, Axios, Jasmine

Other: OOP, test-driven development, responsive design, RESTful API development, Git/GitHub

Non-technical: Bilingual in native-level English and native-level Spanish.

Projects:

NE-XO

A real-time messaging app with live language translations built with Flask Framework. It uses Socket-IO for WebSocket functionality and Google Cloud Translation API for all translations. Authenticated users are able to create private "meeting rooms" to host their conversation and send invite codes to friends. PostgreSQL and SQL-Alchemy are used to interact with database. Design is responsive so users can use web app on mobile or desktop devices.

ChimieAPI

An API containing resources on all 118 chemical elements. Different API endpoints can provide a resource for just one element, a group of elements or all elements. The API is built using Flask for all endpoints and responds to requests with JSON. The API uses PostgreSQL and SQLAlchemy to interact and store data. Can be used to create interactive applications for students learning about the periodic table.

Education:

Springboard – Software Engineering Track (May 2020 – Present)

The University of Texas at Austin – Bachelor of Arts in Biology (May 2011 – December 2015)

Experience:

Springboard – Software Engineering Student (May 2020 – Present)

- Work on various projects with other engineers. Currently working on software tools that can be used in high school science classrooms including an API used to retrieve information on chemical elements.
- Meet with a Senior Engineer mentor once a week to discuss importance of object-oriented programming, test-driven development and give feedback as to how to improve as a software engineer
- Undergo Code Review with other Senior Engineers upon completion of key projects.

United Airlines – Language Qualified Flight Attendant (February 2016 – Present)

- Build rapport quickly with passengers and crewmembers of different backgrounds
- Responsible for the safety and security of all passengers while delivering great customer service.
- Multiple recognitions from customers and the company, including United 100 Winner 2018 Q3